19 meditation number 19 we had 27 I'm
afraid we will finish that's what I
usually do this what's the second refuge
commitment by the way the first year
refuge commitments are negative don't do
this yeah once you've taken refuge in
Dharma you can't hurt anything or
anybody anymore okay that's the second
refuge commitment is if you were in
Thailand you you heard them recently if
you weren't I mean big May and Phil
teach them every time I guess right so
second refuge commitment don't hurt
other people in the laundry book when we
get to there it's going to say what's a
sign that a person is taking refuge
successfully okay how do you know
someone is a successful refuge taker
okay and what's the answer they're nice
to everybody okay like when you say
under secret Buddhism you know highest
Buddhism what comes in people's minds I
don't know I I think a lot of people see
some people see people killing chickens
and spraying blood on people and some
people say see people having sex and
some people see Lama in a big hat and
going to go
you know but what it really is is
something like I don't know Takia or Rob
messenger or Adam they're just nice
people you think that's a hi-hi tantric
person they are nice to everybody
okay if not they have a special dollar
okay special hat that's how you can tell
oh this person must be practicing hybrid
this is a high Buddhist practitioner
because they're just nice to everybody
okay
just lead to everybody more and more
sweet okay so we're not going to do the
meditation this morning but 19 when you
get to 19 you can think about am i
successful in my refugee practice and
that's why refuge is the basis of
Tundras okay am i being nice to other
people okay if you take refuge then it
means you understand that things are
coming from you if you understand that
things are coming from you you will
always be nice okay so the fact that a
person understands refuge is that they
never hurt anybody okay they don't say
things that hurt other people they don't
do things that are dangerous like
talking on your cell phone when you're
driving you know they're just super
careful not to hurt other people
you know somebody was telling me Howard
Connie react to this dinner we had a
really bad dinner the other day and in
some of them now I just think of it like
honey would you think
like how would you talk to this person
and we had it having a sign or anything
Connie would say you really put this on
the plate of different ingredients
[Music]
anyway that's a saying that your message
we kept going to so they they not
decided someone took refuge okay and
that's a sign of tantric practice okay
they're just nice to people so he's
talking about the result of refuge right
which is if you it's that slow time if
you understand emptiness you understand
that nothing happens without you you
behaving some way towards other people
if you understand that which is
dependent origination you take refuge
meaning you don't do things that are
going to hurt you later
and that's protection and then you're a
nice person
so if a person is nice who went to many
DCI programs or something we hope it's
because they understood since Darian and
that's a sign that they have refuge okay
so obviously it's difficult to judge if
other people what they're thinking right
but we can judge what we're thinking and
we can decide
about ourselves you know in my a
successful refuge sticker okay so that's
meditation number 19